譯者:微博@Emtee
時光荏苒
As life progresses,
影像迷離
images blur.
獨留回憶
All that remains are memories.
真真假假
Some of them true,some of them false.
我清楚地記得她
I remember her well.
至少我覺得是這樣
At least I think I do.
她是一名戰士
She was a warrior.
在舊時代 你必須
In the old century you had to be,
爲生存而戰
in order to survive.
悍女
譯者：微博@Emtee
第一章
啓示
吸氣 呼氣 就像她那樣
Breathe in and out, the way she does.
現在 用力 快
And now, push. Now!
非常感謝
Thank you so much.
再見
Bye.
你過幾天再來 對嗎
See you in a couple of days, right?
媽媽
Mama...
走嗎
Are you coming?
- 早上好 - 你好 莉茲
- Good morning! - Hi, Liz!
給
Here.
我不准
莉茲 這孩子得學怎麽開槍
Liz, the boy's gotta learn how to shoot.
我不允許
他不管怎麽樣都會學的
Well, he's gonna do it anyway.
在這學總好過偷偷在別處學
Better here than sneaking off somewhere else.
- 你嚇到你母親了 - 她不是我母親
- You're scaring your mother. - She ain't my mother.
要防備假先知
Beware of false prophets,
他們到你們這裏來 外面披著羊皮
who come to you in sheep's clothing...
裏面却是殘暴的狼
For inwardly, they are ravening wolves.
耶穌是保護你們和你們家人
Jesus is the Shepherd who protects you
不受那些狼所害的牧羊人
and your family from those wolves.
而我是祂的犬
And I am his dog.
讓迷途羔羊
The sheepdog that gets the lambs back on track
重回正軌的牧羊犬
when they stray off the path.
你們有些人已經走入歧途了 對嗎
And some of you have strayed, haven't you?
你們是怎麽想的
What do you people think?
覺得神會同意?
That god is well disposed towards you?
我就直說吧
Let me set things straight.
應當離群的那些去的是地獄
Those who deserve it, go to hell.
我能跟你們講講地獄
I could tell you about hell.
講講那裏的火焰
About its flames.
講講那裏的痛苦
About the pain.
我肯定你們已經試想過那裏的樣子
I'm sure you people have tried to imagine what it's like.
實則更糟
It's worse.
懲罰要來臨了
Retribution is coming.
現在我們唱歌吧
Now, let us join in singing.
與主同行
Abide with me.
你沒事吧
You all right?
謝謝
Thank you.
你好 先生 這是我女兒 珊慕
How're you doing, sir? This is my daughter, Sam.
我兒子 馬修 還有...
My boy, Matthew. And, uh...
我妻子
My wife.
你去哪了
Where were you?
那個人不是本地的
That man is a stranger here,
他還不認識這裏的人
he doesn't know anybody yet.
我還以爲你會有點同情心
I'd have expected a little more compassion from you.
怎麽了 怎麽了 怎麽了
What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong?
深呼吸 好嗎
Just breathe, all right?
呼吸 深呼吸就好
Breathe, just breathe.
大家都出去 我們不需要凑熱鬧的
Everybody outside.We don't need no busybodies.
出去啊 快出去
Go on, get. Get out!
- 會沒事的 - 內森 我覺得你最好也出去
- You'll be all right. - Nathan, I think you better go outside too.
有些事是男人不該看的
Some things aren't meant for a man's eyes.
會沒事的 對嗎 莉茲
It's gonna be just fine, right, Liz?
你會照顧好她的 對吧
You're gonna take care of her, right?
保證?
Promise?
我要出去了 好嗎 我愛你 我愛你
I'm going to be right outside, okay? I love you. I love you.
你照顧好她
You take care of her.
把你身後的門關上
Close the door behind you.
會沒事的 親愛的
It's gonna be all right, honey.
孩子的頭太大了
The baby's head is too big.
什麽意思
What's that supposed to say?
我們得在孩子和母親之間做出選擇
We're going to have to choose between the baby and the mother.
沒法同時救兩個
Can't save both of them.
必須都救
You have to.
你母親說一切都會好的
Your mother said everything would be all right.
不要 我想待著 我想幫忙
No, I wanna stay. I wanna help.
嘿 裏面怎麽樣了
Hey... how's it going in there?
一切都好嗎
Everything all right?
是嗎
Yeah?
用力 阿比 使出全力 加把勁
Push, Abby. Hard as you can now, come on!
好樣的
Good girl!
孩子在哪
Where's the baby?
我想看看我的孩子 他在哪
I wanna see my baby. Where is he?
把我的孩子給我
Give me my baby!
這不是你的錯
It ain't your fault.
耶和華賜予了 耶和華又拿走了
The lord gives and the lord takes away.
這和耶和華無關
這和牧師有關
牧師?
The reverend?
莉茲
Liz...
牧師是神的代表
The reverend is a man of god.
你所認爲的幷不是事實
You're seeing things that ain't there.
耶穌死後復活了
If Jesus came back to life after he was dead...
阿比蓋爾的孩子不會嗎
Couldn't that happen to Abigail's baby, too?
你能給我塗臉嗎
Can you face-paint me?
你能幫我一下嗎
我忙著呢 看不出嗎
I'm doing something. Can't you tell?
我們來看下情况
We've come to see if everything's all right.
一切正常
Everything's just fine.
你們無需浪費時間
No reason for you folks to go wasting your time.
我們想親眼看下
We'd like to look for ourselves.
最好不要 醫生一小時後就到
Rather not. There's a doctor coming in an hour,
他看更好
it's better if he takes a look.
牧師安排的
The reverend arranged it.
你們好
Hello!
- 什麽情况 - 莉茲
- What the hell? - Liz!
莉茲
Liz!
下來 莉茲
You get down here, Liz!
下來
You get down here!
我要看到你的臉
I wanna see your face.
內森 別把氣出在我兒子身上
Nathan! Don't take it out on my boy!
我們能好好談談
We can talk about this like decent folk!
我跟你沒過節 伊萊
I got no quarrel with you, Eli!
我是來找你妻子的
I'm here for your wife.
她得爲她的罪行受到懲罰
She's gotta be punished for her sins.
她得在火刑柱上被燒死
She's gotta burn at the stake, Eli!
理智些 內森
Try to be reasonable now, Nathan.
我理解你的悲痛 相信我
I know your sorrow, believe me.
我也失去過心愛之人 記得嗎
I lost a loved one too, remember?
我知道你的悲痛讓你失去了理智
I know you're out of your mind with grief,
但相信我 你的痛苦會過去的 就和我的一樣
but believe me, your pain will pass, just like mine did!
我能很容易地接受你說的
I could accept that real easy,
只要那個沒舌頭的謀殺犯死在火刑柱上
as long as that tongueless murderess ends up at the stake!
我要她受到懲罰
I demand retribution!
你知道她做了什麽嗎 伊萊
You know what she did, Eli?
她殺了我的寶貝兒子
She murdered my baby boy.
就在他能受洗之前 她殺了他
Before he could even be baptized, she murdered him.
現在他會怎麽樣
What's gonna happen to him now?
你覺得他會找到救贖嗎
Do you think he's gonna find salvation?
你知道她怎麽做的嗎 伊萊
You know how she did it, Eli?
我看過他
I seen him.
他的大腦外露
His brains had leaked out.
你妻子弄裂了他的頭骨
Your wife broke his skull.
她破開了他的頭骨
She cracked his skull wide open!
她該爲此下地獄
She should go to hell for this!
够了
That will be enough.
你遭受著痛苦...
There has been suffering...
威士忌讓你胡言亂語
It is the whiskey talking now.
當下解决不了問題
This is not the moment to solve this.
她該下地獄 牧師
She belongs in hell, reverend.
他傷到你了嗎
Did he do you any harm?
不要讓牧師進來
他剛剛幫我們脫離了困境
He just helped us out of a real fix.
我也能來一杯嗎
Do I get one, too?
你還太年輕
You ain't old enough for that yet.
幹嘛對這孩子這麽苛刻
Why be so hard on the boy?
他爲了保護家人才有所行動
He only acted to protect his family.
他這樣做就是成年人了
That makes him an adult.
他母親不希望他擺弄槍
His mother doesn't want him playing with guns.
年輕人想手持步槍是很自然的事
It's natural for a young man to want to hold a rifle in his hands.
我能把我這杯給馬修喝嗎
May I offer my glass to Matthew?
我想你該去睡覺了 馬修
I think it's about time you went back to bed, Matthew.
- 爸爸 - 快 喝了
- Aw, dad! - Come on, drink up.
如果那孩子
None of this would have happened
健康完好地被生下 就不會有這種事
if that baby had been born in perfect health.
但莉茲對此無能爲力
But Liz couldn't do nothing about that.
她决定了誰生誰死
She decided who was to live and who was to die.
那個决定屬￿神 也只屬￿神
That decision belongs to god, and god only.
她爲什麽不把那個選擇給留給他呢
Why did she not leave that choice up to him?
也許我該去把她帶來
Maybe I should go fetch her.
我知道你在那裏
I know you're there,
我也知道你能聽到我說話
and I know you can hear me.
或許你沒舌頭
You may have no tongue,
但你的耳朵沒問題
but there is nothing wrong with your ears.
你心中爲什麽會起疑
Why do doubts rise in your heart?
你爲什麽會煩惱
Why are you troubled?
你晚上怎麽入睡的
How do you sleep at night?
做謀殺犯是什麽感覺
How does it feel to be a murderess?
你知道我爲什麽來這裏嗎
Do you know why I'm here?
我是來懲罰你的
I'm here to punish you.
你愛這個家嗎
Do you love this family?
我見過你女兒了
I've looked at your daughter.
她就快是個年輕女人了
She's almost a young woman already.
你在這啊
There you are.
我得走了
I must be going.
對內森請不要懷恨在心
Please don't bear a grudge against Nathan in your heart.
失去孩子是最難以承受的事
Losing a child is the worst thing a body can go through.
我剛跟你妻子也這麽說了
I was just talking to your wife about that same thing.
你都沒感謝他
You didn't even thank him.
實際上 你都沒有跟他打招呼
Fact is, you didn't even say hello to him.
我們必須離開這裏
莉茲 內森會恢復理智的
Liz, Nathan will come around.
對了 你知道嗎
Right, you know what?
給我一兩天時間
Give me a couple of days.
我找人來看管羊
I'll get someone to come in for the sheep...
然後我們去我爸那裏待一段時間
And then we'll go up to my pa's for a bit.
反正那裏就他一個人
He's all alone up there anyway.
爸爸
Dad?
待在這裏
我要去談談 這得有個了結
I'm just going to talk. This has got to stop.
先是開槍打我們的窗戶 現在又這樣
First shootin' our windows up, now this.
駕 走吧
Yah! Come on!
駕 駕
Yah! Yah!
我要你和你母親待在一起
I want you to stay with your mother.
她不是我母親
She ain't my mother.
- 馬修 - 你會需要我幫忙的
- Matthew! - You're gonna need my help.
好吧 只要你別惹麻煩
All right, as long as you stay outside.
但我爲什麽不能進去玩呢
But why can't i just play inside?
我要你在我身旁
爲什麽
Why?
因爲我說了算
我爲什麽不能幫忙
And why can't I help out?
別再問問題了 你待在這裏唱唱歌
我覺得現在可以把遮眼布摘掉了
I think we can take that blindfold off, now.
但我保證過
But I promised.
你母親不會介意
Your mother won't mind.
她有很多事要做
She has a lot to do.
好了 看見沒
Here, see?
一切都會好的
Everything will be fine.
媽媽呢
And mama?
她得在穀倉幹活
She had to work in the barn.
她不想你過去 記得嗎
And she did not want you there, do you remember?
我想和你談談你的母親
I would like to talk to you about your mother.
內森
Nathan!
他們搬走了
They've gone and moved.
莉茲
Liz?
你在哪
Where are you?
他帶走了珊慕
別 內森離開了 阿比蓋爾也是
No, no, Nathan's gone. And Abigail.
收拾好 搬走了
Packed up, moved out.
牧師 他把我鎖在穀倉裏
你去哪了
Oh! Where'd you get to, huh?
你嚇到你母親了
You scared your mother.
你讓她擔心死了
Had her worried sick.
要我給你塗臉嗎
今天下午 你和牧師說了些什麽
他說到我了嗎
媽媽 你是邪惡的嗎
Mama, are you evil?
牧師說你殺了一個人
The reverend said you murdered a man.
他說他是來懲罰你的
He says he's here to punish you.
要把你帶回他來的地方
To take you back where he came from.
爲什麽
Why?
因爲她愛你
Because she loves you.
開槍打死我
Shoot me.
在你身後
Behind you.
求你了
Please.
終結我的痛苦
Stop the pain.
帶她們去爺爺那
Take them to grandpa.
媽媽 媽媽
Mama? Mama?
是那個牧師 他把我弄醒了
It was the reverend. He woke me up.
駕 駕
Yah! Yah!
第二章
出走
嘿 你是誰 叫什麽名字
阿明 她醒了
下車
快點下車
喬安娜 我叫喬安娜
Joanna. My name is Joanna.
我要把她賣給弗蘭克 賺一筆錢
- 不要啊 - 閉嘴
弗蘭克的地獄
弗蘭克
Frank!
阿明
Meng!
你好啊
喂 我有好東西給你
我就下來
漂亮點才行 過來
把頭發放下來
阿明 瞧瞧你 你個混蛋發財了啊
Meng, you prosperous fucker, you. Look at you.
這位是?
And what do we have here?
我叫喬安娜
My name's Joanna.
很高興認識你
Well, it is a pleasure to meet you.
來 轉一圈 讓我看看你
Come on now, spin around, let me get a look at you.
不錯啊
There you are.
- 莎莉 - 什麽事
- Sally! - Yeah.
你能弄杯冰檸水
Would you be so kind as to treat Joanna here
招待下這邊的喬安娜嗎
to a glass of cold lemonade?
當然可以 來吧 親愛的
Yeah, but of course. Come, honey.
好了 阿明 我們來談正事
All right, meng, let's talk fucking Turkey.
給
Here you go.
看呐 新來的
Lookie here! Fresh meat.
一口吞了 小姑娘
Swallow it right on down, girlie.
很快你就要吞別的東西了
Soon you'll be swallowing something else.
- 你叫什麽 姑娘 - 喬安娜
- What's your name, girl? - Joanna.
你爸爸帶你來的嗎
Did your daddy bring you here?
不是? 你確定嗎
No? Are you sure?
難道他不是覺得你漂亮
Didn't he just think you were so good,
他得讓這世上的其他人也知道?
he had to let the rest of the world in on it, too?
你以爲你能去哪啊
Whoa, there now, where do you think you're going?
他們沒帶上我就走了
They're leaving without me!
沒錯 但別擔心
Yes, they are, but don't you worry about a thing
因爲從現在起 你就住這了 親愛的
'cause from now on, this is where you live, darling.
就這裏
Right here.
好了 去弄弄乾淨吧
Now, come on now. Let's get you cleaned up.
沒錯
Yes.
噓 噓
Shh, shh.
爽 爽
Yeah, yeah!
所以那就是我們在這做的工作
So that's the work we do around here.
我們只要一直呻吟
And we do all the moaning and groaning
就能確保更快完事
because that makes sure it's over faster.
- 爲什麽 - 爲什麽 因爲男人喜歡
- Why? - Why? That's what men like.
那麽...你出過血嗎
So, um... You ever bled yet?
你兩腿之間 親愛的
'Twixt your legs, honey.
這沒什麽羞耻的 出過吧?
It's nothing to be ashamed of. You have, haven't you?
對嗎 好吧 這暫且是
Yeah? Well, then, that's gonna be our little secret
我們的小秘密 好嗎
for the time being, okay?
現在 你去睡吧
Now, you go to bed.
你是誰
And who are you?
你叫什麽 姑娘
What's your name, girl?
喬安娜
Joanna.
弗蘭克 跟她上樓什麽價
Frank, what's it cost to go upstairs with this one?
拜托 弗雷德 你出不起
Come on now, Fred, you cannot afford her.
我不這麽認爲
Oh, I don't know about that.
今天我的牌運可他媽好了
I got pretty damn lucky at cards today.
嘿 伊士曼
Hey, eastman.
我欲火焚身 想和你做
I'm horny as hell and I feel like doing you!
給你免費來一炮怎麽樣
What would you say to a free ride, huh?
這可不是你說了算
That ain't yours to decide.
錢我自己出
I'll pay for it myself.
該死 莎莉 這種事你一直瞞著我 是嗎
Damn, Sally, what, you been holding out on me now, huh?
這樣可以 但她得看著
I'll go along with that. But then she gets to watch.
- 不行 - 那就算了
- No way. - Then, it's no deal.
我覺得這是個好主意
Oh, it sounds like a fine idea to me.
我肯定這會很有教育意義
It'll be most educational, I'm sure.
怎麽了 你不喜歡嗎 寶貝
What's wrong, don't you like it, honeybunch?
爽
譯禇 覹愽 Emtёё
Oh, yeah.
打我
Hit me.
- 什麽 - 打我
- What? - Hit me!
不行 我不會那麽做
No, I ain't gonna do that.
打我啊 該死的
Hit me, god damn it!
這樣可不行 伊士曼
I'm not taking this, eastman.
再打我
Hit me again.
Hit me again!
別 別 別 別 別開槍
No, no, no, no, don't shoot!
別開槍 我沒關係 喬安娜
Don't shoot. I don't mind it, Joanna.
這只是場游戲 對吧
It's just a game, right?
再動手我就開槍了
You do that again and I'm going to shoot.
請把槍放下
Please put the gun down.
你敢 繼續對準我
Don't you ever. Just keep pointing it at me.
你敢放下槍試試
Don't you dare drop that gun on me.
這就對了 繼續對準我
That's right. Keep pointing it at me.
你敢放下試試
Don't you dare.
我要掐死她
I'm gonna strangle the life out of her!
開槍打我啊
Shoot me!
動手啊 喬安娜 開槍打我 該死的
Do it, Joanna. Shoot me, god damn it!
開槍啊 該死 婊子
Shoot, god damn it, bitch!
我能看出你會是個不錯的小妓女
You're gonna make a fine little whore, i can see that already.
我打賭你也能把我弄得非常乾淨
I just bet that you can make me real nice and clean too.
或許全世界把我們美麗的城市畢斯瑪司
The whole world may see our fair city of bismuth
看成是索多瑪和蛾摩拉
as a place of sodom and gomorrah,
但規矩在這裏是管用的
but rules do apply here.
不准妓女射殺客人還不受懲罰
A whore cannot be allowed to shoot down her customers with impunity.
我哥哥經營地獄酒館是爲了
My brother runs the inferno as a place
讓辛勤工作的礦工們
where hard-working miners
能找到應得的消遣
can find well-deserved recreation.
這必須保持下去
That must remain so,
也會保持下去
and so it will.
讓此事警示所有人吧
Let this be an example.
別這樣...
Come on now...
一個礦鎮需要有組織的娛樂
A mining town has a need for organized entertainment.
我得讓這裏的客人感到安全
And I need to know that customers here feel safe.
所以我把我弟弟齊克帶到了畢斯瑪司
That's why I brought my brother Zeke to bismuth.
他是個好警長 這個鎮配不上他
He's a better sheriff than this town deserves.
地獄酒館的每個人都知道
Everybody at the inferno knows
一個姑娘哪怕抓傷了客人
that if a girl so much as scratches a customer
她都會受到懲罰
she's gonna be punished.
所以莎莉知道她會面臨什麽
So Sally knew what she had coming.
可他吊死她了
But he strangled her.
是啊...我知道 我也很難過
Yeah... I know, it hurt me too.
該死的 她是跟我最久的員工之一
Damn, she was one of my oldest employees.
但是規矩是規矩
But rules are rules.
你不守規矩 你就有罪
If you don't obey the rules, you're guilty.
你有罪 你就要付出代價
And if you're guilty, you're gonna pay.
你明白的 對嗎
You understand that, don't you? Hmm?
告訴我你明白
Tell me you understand.
你知道我第一次跟女孩上床是幾歲嗎
You know how old i was when I first went to bed with a girl?
我21歲
I was 21.
Twenty-one.
那時齊克14歲
While Zeke, he was 14.
而我還得偷看
I got to watch, though.
從窺孔裏偷看他
I spied on him through the peephole.
那之前 我一直不理解其中的樂趣
I never did see what all the fuss was about.
也不理解大家所談論的那些事
You know, what everybody talked about.
我理解不了
I couldn't see it.
你不再是個孩子了
You're not a child anymore.
我不是很久了
I haven't been for a long time.
是時候了
The time has come.
我會溫柔的
I'm gonna be gentle.
就是這樣
That's right.
帥哥 你好棒
Oh, stud, you sure are good.
喬安娜
Joanna!
弗蘭克要决鬥了
Frank is in a gunfight!
嘿 搞什麽啊 我就快完事了
Hey, what the hell! I'm almost done.
你看到沒
You see that?
下次讓她一起來 你覺得如何
What do you say we have her join us next time?
他來了
Here he is.
這是我和弗蘭克之間的事
This is just between me and frank.
我只要一場公平對决
All I want is a fair fight.
那你來這裏幹嘛
Then what are you doing here?
讓他爽進地獄吧
Blow him to hell!
沒錯
Yeah!
我不是個暴力的人
I'm not a violent man.
我常和數字打交道
I usually work with numbers.
但現在我站在你面前
But now, I'm standing here in front of you
是要開槍打死你 弗蘭克
to shoot you dead, frank.
我女兒因你而死
My daughter is dead because of you.
你這樣的男人覺得自己的所作所爲不會有後果
It's men like you who think their actions have no consequences,
你這樣的男人在使這國家變樣
who are making the country turn into what it's turning into.
所以爲了我的女兒
So, for my daughter's sake,
爲了每一個人的女兒
for every daughter's sake,
我不得不殺了你
I have to kill you.
因爲我是一位父親
Because I am a father.
所以你會數數
So you can count.
也會講屁話
And you can sure as shit talk.
但我們都想知道的是
But what we all wanna know is,
你會開槍嗎
can you shoot?
我們什麽時候私奔
So, when do we elope?
去哪
Where to?
哪都行
Anywhere.
只要是我們能得到自由的地方
Wherever we can be free.
但我們在這也算自由
But we are free here. Sort of.
不算
No, we're not.
你知道的
And you know it.
給我塗臉
Face-paint me.
什麽
What?
用你的手指塗我的臉
Paint my face with your fingers.
你讓我想起了我的妻子
You, uh, remind me of my wife.
但你衣著更美 聞上去更香 長得更漂亮
But you dress better, you smell better, you look better.
謝謝
Thank you.
不准接吻
No fucking kissing.
我說了 不准接吻
I said, no kissing!
不准接吻 該死的
No kissing! God damn it!
你要請我喝酒還怎麽
So, are you gonna buy me that drink, or what?
當然 威士忌
Sure. Whiskey.
我警告過你了 你個狗娘養的
I warned you, you son of a bitch!
沒人能吻我 懂嗎
Nobody kisses me, do you understand?
該死的婊子 你咬掉了我的舌頭
Fucking whore, you bit my tongue off.
弗蘭克 弗蘭克
Frank? Frank?
姑娘 這次你居然真咬了
Oh, girl, you really gone and done it now.
我警告了他六次
I warned him six times!
你警告的那傢伙是金礦上的重要人物
Well, the fella you warned is kind of important up at the gold mine.
現在我的酒館裏全他媽是
Now, I got me a whole saloon
喝醉的白痴 全叫著要給懲罰
full of drunken fucking idiots all howling for retribution.
叫他們見鬼去吧
Tell 'em to go fuck themselves.
給他們免費喝一杯好了
Give them a drink on the house or something.
你們覺得我會因爲你們這些姑娘
Well, you think I'm gonna waste my hard-earned money
壞了規矩而浪費我辛苦賺來的錢?
because you girls refuse to obey the fucking rules?
給我起來 快走
Get the fuck up! Come on!
- 出來 - 去你們媽的
- Get out there! - Fuck you!
邁克在哪
Now, where's Mike?
我要她受到懲罰
I demand retribution!
她會的 邁克
You're gonna get it, Mike.
瞧 畢斯瑪司的規矩很明確
You see, the rules in bismuth are clear,
所有客人都會得到應有的尊重
and all customers will get the respect they got coming.
吊死這愚蠢的妓女
Hang the stupid whore!
不行 伊麗莎白不會被吊死
No, no, Elizabeth here, she's not gonna hang.
必須吊死她 弗蘭克
Gotta hang her, frank!
邁克現在也沒死 對嗎
Mike ain't dead now neither, is he?
但他因她的無法無天而受害
But he was a victim of her lawlessness,
所以他能給個提議
so he gets to make a fucking proposal.
會是什麽提議呢 邁克
Now what's it gonna be, Mike? Huh?
你想免費幹她一周? 是這樣嗎
You want this free pussy for a week? Is that it?
你給我把那婊子的舌頭割了
You cut that fucking bitch's tongue off!
你想以物換物 是吧 邁克
You want a trade, Mike, huh?
你想以眼還眼? 你是想這樣嗎 邁克
You want an eye for an eye? Is that what you want, Mike?
每天用酒精沖洗五次
Rinse it five times a day with alcohol
應該會比你預料的要愈合得更快
and it should heal up sooner than you'd think.
不能吃固體食物 不能口交
No solid foods. No blow jobs.
她還能再說話嗎
Will she ever be able to talk again?
沒太大可能
Not much chance of that.
給
Here you go.
聾啞人手語詞典
再見
Goodbye.
我
I...
跳舞
Dance...
在周二?
On Tuesday?
我只喝酒
I only drink
在周二
on Tuesdays.
我只在周二喝酒
I only drink on Tuesdays.
我
I...
殺
Kill...
弗蘭克?
Frank?
這是自殺
That's suicide.
但他們會追捕你
But they'll come after you.
此外 你怎麽打算呢
Besides, what're you gonna do?
去別的妓院工作嗎
Work in some other cathouse?
請別那麽做
Please don't do it.
我無法忍受對你的思念
I couldn't stand to miss you.
別以爲
Don't think
這地方無法紀 不敬神
just because this is a lawless, godless place
你們的所作所爲就不會有後果
that your actions will go without consequences.
女士們 你們想死後下地獄嗎
Ladies, do you want to end up in hell?
漂亮的衣服愚弄不了任何人
The nice clothing doesn't fool anybody.
我知道你們是誰
I know who you are
我知道你們是什麽
and I know what you are.
你們的父親知道後會怎麽想
What would your fathers think if they knew?
你們的母親會落泪
Your mothers weep.
你們的父親會因耻辱而挖出自己的眼睛
Your fathers pluck out their eyes in shame!
婚姻中介
你好
Good day.
我有東西給你 進來吧
I have something for you.Come.
我已經找到了一個人
I've managed to find someone who doesn't mind
他不介意娶沒舌頭的女人
marrying a woman without a tongue,
不過路有些遠
but it will take some traveling.
他六個月前就是個鰥夫了
He's been a widower since the last six months.
他在找一個會下厨的妻子
He's looking for a wife who can cook
還要不介意他有個兒子
and who doesn't mind that he already has a son.
跟我猜的差不多
No, I figured as much.
我們會熱情地歡迎你
"We will welcome you with open arms
幷保證讓你儘快有家的感覺
"and make sure you feel right at home, as quickly as possible.
敬上 等等等等 這裏有張照片
"Respectfully yours." And so on and so forth, and there's a picture.
你會有個真正的家庭
You're gonna have a real family.
我要怎麽做呢
How am I gonna do that?
我們是姐妹?
We're sisters?
弗蘭克會殺了我們
Frank would kill us.
不行 世事難料
No, you never know.
等你獲得你新丈夫的信任後
And when you've convinced your new husband,
你能從那邊幫我付馬車費
you can pay for the stagecoach from down there.
你覺得你的行程要多久
How long you think you'll need?
你們兩個得馬上出來
You two gotta come right away.
某個傢伙剛付了一大筆現金
Some fella just paid a whole pile of cash
包下了地獄酒館 你們快點
to buy out the inferno. Get your asses moving.
你最後一晚還得工作
Your last night and you got to work too.
好了 聽好
All right now, listen up!
我們在月末通常賺不到錢
Usually, we don't earn Jack-shit at the end of the month.
賈姬 你他媽給我馬上閉嘴
Jackie, shut the fuck up right fucking now
不然我他媽親手讓你閉上
or I'm gonna fucking make you.
這個客人是天賜之福
This customer right here is a godsend
他今晚把你們全包下了
and he bought the right to all of y'all this evening
要是他成了常客
and if he becomes a regular customer,
我就會豐厚地獎賞你們
well, you can all expect a big, fat, fucking bonus, courtesy of me.
但我要你們完全保證
But I demand total commitment here.
不管發生什麽
I mean, whatever happens,
不管他他媽想要什麽
whatever the fuck he wants,
他都會得到滿足
he is gonna get it.
如果有人
Now if anybody,
有人做了什麽 給我毀了這事
I mean, anyone does anything to ruin it for me...
就會受到懲罰
Well, they're gonna be punished.
會受到比以前更嚴重的懲罰
Shit, they're gonna be punished worse than I've punished anyone before.
總之 你們好好表現
But with that fucking said, you do a good job, and, uh,
他就會都要了
shit, he'll take you all.
這事要給我辦成
I want this one.
好了 快來
All right now, come on!
你會喜歡這排場的
You are gonna like this.
沒錯 就是這樣
That's right, there you are.
我的小寶貝們
My little doves.
看呐
Now, will you look at that, huh?
這兩個很年輕 很嫩
These two right here, they're real young, real fresh.
沒被動過 你懂的
Untouched, if you know what I mean.
我們這裏各種各樣的都有
We got all kinds here.
我們有中國人 如果你喜歡這種的話
We've got Chinese, if you like that kind of thing.
這一個 她叫賈姬
Oh, this one here, she's Jackie.
我能看出 賈姬喜歡你
Jackie likes you, i can tell.
你想要的 我們這裏都有
We've got anything you want here.
你內心的所有欲望
All your heart's desire.
就在地獄酒館裏
Right here in the inferno.
這一個 她性子很烈
Oh, this one here, well, she got a fire in her.
我不得不割了她的舌頭
And I had to cut out her tongue
讓她聽話
just to keep her in line.
幸好她沒法回嘴
Good thing, she can't talk back.
先生 你很有品位
You have fine taste, sir.
這一個 她對我來說是個謎
This one right here, well, she is a mystery to me.
她是我從一夥游歷的浪人那買下的
I bought her from a band of traveling gypsies.
你懂的 多種多樣
You know, colorful types.
該死 我都不知道她的真名
Damn, I don't even know her real name.
就是她
She's the one.
選得太好了 先生
Well, that's an excellent choice, sir.
我能推薦其他幾個姑...
May I suggest a couple of other gi...
就只要她
Only her.
但你包下的是整個地獄酒館
But you paid for the whole inferno.
我包下是不想被人看到這種事
I paid not to be seen doing this.
今晚花了我很多錢
This evening has cost me a lot of money.
你的聲音有什麽問題嗎 你不能說話嗎
Is there something wrong with your voice? Can't you talk?τгаηslаτed ьγ ωeiьо-Eмτee
我能說話
Yes, I can.
你想要我給你跳舞嗎
Would you like me to dance for you?
爲了找到你 我不得不等待很久
I had to wait a long time to find you.
我非常失望 我想過很多情况 但不是這種
I am very disappointed. I had considered many things, but not this.
這就是你想要的嗎
Is this what you wanted?
這就是你所追求的嗎
What you looked for?
我已準備好原諒你所有的罪
I am prepared to forgive all your sins.
我也有罪
I have also sinned.
我會在地獄中被永遠焚燒
I am going to burn in hell forever.
我放弃了去天堂的權利
I gave up the right to go to heaven.
但是你讓我這麽做的
But you made me do it.
只有你能拯救我
And only you can save me.
- 別這樣 - 沒錯
- No. - Yes.
我有罪是因爲我們應該先完成儀式
I have sinned because we should have finished the ceremony first.
這是使徒保羅寫在哥林多前書裏的
Paul, the apostle, wrote it in the first corinthians.
- 幫幫我 喬安娜 - 我幫不了
- Help me, Joanna. - I can't.
那我們兩個都會下地獄
Then we shall both burn in hell.
我是來拯救你的 好讓你能拯救我
I am here to save you, so that you can save me.
我會讓你這麽做的 你知道我會的
I will make you do it. You know I will.
我不會讓你再那麽做了
I won't let you do that again.
我會先殺了你
I'll kill you first.
我嘗試了 你讓我別無選擇
I tried. You leave me no choice.
救命 來人啊
Help! Somebody... ah!
來人救命啊
Somebody, help! Ah!
- 你是我的 這是神的旨意 - 救命
- You are mine! It is god's will! - Help!
救命
Help!
救命 來人啊
Help! Somebody!
出去
Get out!
你個賤人
You whore!
今晚你要跟我走
You're coming with me tonight.
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.
你不會讓我惹上麻煩 對嗎
You're not gonna get me into trouble, are you?
你確定嗎
Are you sure about this?
好了
All right.
我辦不到
I can't do this.
你是伊麗莎白·布蘭迪嗎
Are you Elizabeth brundy?
你確定你要開始這段行程嗎
Are you sure you're up to making this trip?
好運
Well, good luck.
別讓人看到傷口 依然很新
Don't let anyone see that for a while. It's still pretty fresh.
第三章
起因
我們在天上的父 願人都尊你的名爲聖 願你的國降臨
願你的旨意行在地上 如同行在天上
我們日用的飲食今日賜給我們
免我們的債
And forgive us our trespasses,
如同我們免了人的債
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
不叫我們遇見試探
And lead us not into temptation,
但救我們脫離凶惡
but deliver us from evil.
因爲國度
For thine is the kingdom
權柄 榮耀 全是你的
and the power and the glory,
直到永遠 阿門
forever and ever. Amen.
就今晚吧
Tonight.
喬安娜還是在講荷蘭語
Joanna is still speaking Dutch.
我要追究你的責任
I hold you responsible for that.
我會祈求耶和華的幫助
I'll pray for the lord's assistance.
作爲妻子 你有你的職責
As a wife, you have your duties.
妻子對自己的身體沒有主權
"The wife does not have authority over her own body
丈夫才有 請跟我來吧
"but yields it to her husband." Please come with me.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
你讓我別無選擇
You leave me no choice.
我們知道我們爲什麽來這裏
We know why we came here.
這裏是神的國度
This is god's nation.
耶和華給這個美麗的新國家賜予了祂的恩典
The lord shed his grace on this beautiful new country.
這是我們的出埃及記
This was our exodus.
在這座丘陵上的城市
In this city on a hill,
我們將發展一個更純粹的基督教
we will develop a purer form of christianity.
我們不是都同意
Hadn't we all agreed
拋開舊俗嗎
to leave the old language behind?
我們不是都發誓要在這裏做得更好嗎
Hadn't we sworn to do things better over here?
新世界會把我們從舊世界的罪中解脫
The new world would free us from the sins of the old.
我們是人類的耀眼希望
We are the bright hope of humanity.
這裏是應許之地
This is the promised land,
來到這裏 我們就都成了神選之人
and by coming here, we have become his chosen people.
阿加莎
Agatha,
你能告訴大家你是怎麽領受到召喚的嗎
would you tell everyone how you received the calling?
我在家削土豆時
I was at home, peeling potatoes,
出現了巨大白光
when this huge white light appeared.
我看見白光中有個英俊的年輕男子
In that light, i saw a beautiful young man
有著白色翅膀
with white wings.
我問他是不是天使
I asked if he was an angel,
這個年輕男子點點頭 露出了微笑
and the young man nodded and smiled.
阿裏
Arie,
你能和我們分享一下你目睹的事嗎
would you be so kind to share your story of witness with us?
我的差不多一樣
For me, it was more or less the same thing,
但出現的不是男的
but it wasn't a man.
在我面前出現的是個美麗的年輕女子
It was a beautiful young woman who showed herself to me.
看見沒 我們都是神選之人
You see? We are the chosen people.
顯聖這種事幷非在任何人身上
A visitation like that is not something that happens
都會發生 你必須爭取它
to just anybody. You have to earn it.
安娜
Anna,
你能上前來嗎
would you please come to the front?
你怎麽說 安娜
What about you, Anna?
你領受到召喚了嗎
Have you received the calling yet?
我還沒受到這樣的祝福
I have not been blessed in such a way.
在我們社區  每個成年人都領受到了召喚 而你却沒有
In our community, everyone of age has received such a calling, you have not.
安娜 你做了什麽讓神如此憤怒
What did you do, Anna, to anger god this much?
我自己的妻子
My own wife,
沒法受到神的青睞
who cannot find the lord's favor.
你讓我感到耻辱
I am ashamed of you.
天父
Father,
我祈求我妻子對你和對我的愛會增加
I pray that my wife will grow in her love for you,and me.
願她對我們的愛 注入所有真心
May she love us with all her heart,
所有靈魂 所有思想和所有努力
all her soul, all her mind, and all her might.
賜予我力量 引領她通向
Give me the strength to lead her to the salvation
你恩典下的救贖
provided by your grace.
以耶穌之名 阿門
In Jesus' name, amen.
親愛的
我要死了
不會的 不會死
這很正常 你這歲數的姑娘都會出現這樣的情况
爲什麽
你現在是女人了 喬安娜
你的身體已做好生孩子的準備
你必須洗洗你女兒
You must wash your daughter.
她不潔淨了
She is unclean.
但他從不幫一點忙
But he never raises a finger to help out.
這是女人的命運
It's a woman's fate.
誰說的
Says who?
聖經
Says the Bible.
這不公平
It's not fair.
你父親是一名教士
Your father's a man of the cloth.
他侍奉神 塵世的家務雜活都留給了他的妻子
He serves god and leaves earthly chores to his wife.
你想幹嘛
What do you want?
讓我們單獨待會兒 我得和這姑娘談談
Leave us alone, i have to talk to the girl.
你母親跟你說了成爲女人意味著什麽嗎
Has your mother told you what it means to be a woman?
說了
Yes.
這血已滲入你的生活
And the blood has penetrated into your life
已驅走你的純潔
and driven out the innocence.
不用多久 男人們就會開始發現你的魅力
It won't be long before men start to find you attractive.
女人 我知道你在偷聽
Woman? I know you're listening.
從現在起 你要把喬安娜當女人來對待
From now on, you must treat Joanna like a woman.
從今天起 猪就由你來管了
As of today, you will do the hogs.
嘿
Hey.
你好 小姐
Hello, lady.
我看到了水泵
I saw the pump.
希望你能
I was hoping you'd be kind enough
讓我解渴
to let me quench my thirst.
請允許我表達我最深切的感謝
Allow me to express my deepest thanks.
你們從哪來
Where are you men from?
說來話長
Oh, that's a long story.
以後有機會再說
Maybe some other time.
他怎麽辦
What about him?
你照顧好他吧
You take care of him.
我猜你是個基督徒
After all, you are a Christian, I assume?
該死的
God damn me.
去馬那
Get the horse.
我父母會發現你們兩個的
My parents would find you two.
然後把該死的馬鞍拿下來
Then get the goddamn saddle.
快走
Go!
快走 離開這裏 快
Go on, get out of here! Go on!
得把該死的子彈取出來
Damn bullet needs to get taken out.
然後我也需要照顧
And I need taking care of too.
我父親會不高興的
My father won't like that.
是啊...
Yeah...
你知道嗎 別他媽告訴他
You know what? Don't fuckin' tell him.
要取了
Here it comes.
我想 是時候自我介紹了
I reckon, it's about time i introduced myself.
我叫塞繆爾
I'm Samuel.
很高興認識你
It's nice to meet you...
喬安娜
Joanna.
謝謝
Thank you.
這姑娘長得真快
The girl is growing fast.
嗨 親愛的
Hi, sweetie.
他在發燒
He's running a fever.
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
因爲據說測體溫的最佳方式
'Cause they say the best way to take someone's temperature
是用嘴唇 是吧
is with the lips, huh?
你現在多大了 孩子
How old are you now, child?
Thirteen.
一個完全成年的女人...
A full-grown woman has...
在生活中有著小女孩不能履行的職責
Has duties in life that a young girl can't fulfill.
是我們的主親自給予的職責
Duties imposed by our lord himself.
請跟我來
Come with me, please.
你母親總不承擔
Your mother does not always assume responsibilities
她應當承擔的職責
the way she should.
她不依從她的自然職責
She does not comply with her natural duties.
你明白我的意思嗎
Do you understand what I mean?
神讓你這麽快成爲女人 是有原因的
God has made you a woman so soon for a reason.
你或許覺得這是詛咒
You might believe it to be a curse,
但祂做的一切都是有原因的
but he has a reason for everything.
你就如使徒保羅筆下所寫的那樣
You have, as the apostle Paul put it,
過了年歲
"passed the flower of your age."
這可不對
This is not right.
你看到血了
You have seen the blood.
她只是個孩子
She's just a child.
我無需回應你 我只回應神
I need not answer to you. Only to god.
不用了 謝謝 安娜
No, thank you, Anna.
我們的神另有安排
Our god has other plans.
不會有事的
It'll be all right.
雙手拿好
Use both hands.
別讓爆破嚇到你
Don't let the blast scare you.
你現在是成年人了 喬安娜
You're a grown woman now, Joanna.
我能和你談會兒嗎
Could I talk to you for a moment?
我想道歉
I want to offer my apologies.
我不讓你行使你的權利
I withheld from you that to which you have a right.
這是我的錯
That was wrong of me.
我接受道歉
Apology accepted.
讓我來彌補吧
Let me make it up to you.
太晚了
It's too late for that.
我看到了你看她的樣子
I have seen how you look at her.
她是你的親生女兒
She's your own daughter.
這是罪
It's a sin.
不一定
It does not have to be.
若有人以爲自己待他的女兒
"If any man thinks that he is behaving himself unseemly
不合宜 女兒也過了年歲
"towards his virgin daughter, if she pass the flower of her age,
事又當行 他就可隨意辦理
"and if need so requires, let him do what he will,
不算有罪 叫二人成親就是了
"he is not sinning, let them marry."
你這肮髒的猪
我要訓教你
You shall be scolded.
好姑娘
Good girl.
你讓人等得真够久的
That sure as hell took long enough.
你去哪
Where are you going?
我去拉屎
Gonna take a crap.
你要我把這個放哪
Where do you want me to put this?
我急需繩子
I need some rope and I need it fast.
能幫我弄到嗎
Can you get that for me?
很好
Good.
我不得不那麽做
I had to do that.
不然他會趁機殺了我
If I hadn't, he'd have killed me at some point.
他死總比我死好
Better him than me, I'd say.
我曾聽過一個故事
I heard that story once,
有關于忍氣吞聲
the one about turning the other cheek and all that.
說那種話的人
The only person who'd say something like that
就是在掌控一切
is someone who's in control.
就是不希望你反抗他
Someone who doesn't want you to stand up to him.
我看見你母親了
I've seen your mother.
她就是那種忍氣吞聲的人
She's the kind of person that turns the other cheek.
你和她一樣嗎
Are you like her?
你爲什麽讓他這麽做
Why do you let him do this?
我絕不會像你這樣
I'll never be like you.
絕不會這麽活下去
This is no way to live.
我寧願死
I'd rather die first.
蛇對女人說
The serpent said to the woman,
你不一定死
"you surely will not die!
因爲神知道 你吃的日子
"For god knows that in the day you eat from it,
眼睛就明亮了
"your eyes will be opened,
你便如神 能知道善惡
"and you will be like god, knowing good and evil."
于是女人見那棵樹的果子好作食物
And when the woman saw that the tree was good for food,
也悅人的眼目
and was a delight to the eyes,
且是可喜愛的 能使人有智慧
and that the tree was desirable to make one wise,
就摘下果子來吃了
she took from its fruit and ate.
然後耶和華神對女人說
And then the lord god said to the woman,
我必多多加增你懷胎的苦楚
"i will greatly multiply your pain in childbirth.
你生産兒女必多受苦楚
"In pain you will bring forth children,
你必戀慕你丈夫
"yet your desire will be for your husband.
你丈夫必管轄你
"And he will rule over you."
這是褻瀆
This is an abomination.
This is an abomination!
她難道不知道她的身體
Does she not know that her body is
是從神那受領的聖靈之殿嗎
the temple of the holy spirit, which she received from god?
這是一種耻辱
This is a disgrace.
她會在地獄受到懲罰
She will be punished in hell.
她會被變成一棵荊棘樹
She will be transformed into a thorny tree,
在折磨之林中 被鷹身女妖所懲罰
and in a tortured wood, she will be punished by harpies,
她們會用利爪挖鑿她
who will dig their sharp talons into her,
直到她鮮血淋漓
until the blood comes flowing down!
主啊
Oh, lord.
原諒我吧
Forgive me.
你知道我試圖讓她
You know I have tried to keep her
堅守在通向悔改的狹窄之路上
on the narrow way to repentance.
但就如馬太福音所言
But like the gospel of Matthew says,
寬廣的路總是通向毀滅
"the way is broad that leads to destruction."
我勸說她
I spoke to her.
我責打她
I chastised her.
但無濟于事
But to no avail.
我失敗了
I failed.
好了 好了
There, there.
沒事了
It's all right.
我到年齡了
I'm old enough.
我知道
I know.
神已經原諒了我
God has forgiven me.
我準備好了
I am ready.
謝謝你 主 謝謝你 全能的主
Thank you, lord. Thank you, almighty.
你看見幷預見一切
You saw, and foresaw all.
你看見我妻子沒做到你對她所期望的
You saw that my wife did not do what you expected of her.
她不愛你 也不愛我 而我女兒會愛的
That she did not love you, or me, as my daughter will.
羅得和他的女兒們結婚了 而她們是他的孩子
Lot lay with his daughters and they bore children unto him.
喬安娜和我要締結婚姻關係
Joanna and I shall enter a state of matrimony
她會懷上我的孩子
and she shall bear my children.
我們會帶給你喜樂與榮耀
We shall be joyous and honor you.
放開我
Let me go!
別害怕
Fear not.
不要
No!
這是神的旨意 我們是祂的選中之人
It is the will of god. We are his chosen ones.
兩個人以神之名許下誓言時
When two people make their vows in the name of the everlasting,
他們會宣稱屬￿彼此 深深相愛
they pronounce their wish to belong to each other fully in love.
他們將一起探尋神想從他們生活中得到什麽
Together they shall search for what god wants from their lives.
他們將一起履行他們的職責
Together they shall perform their duties
幷照顧好他們的家庭
and care for their family.
我父親是徹頭徹尾的混蛋
My father was a real bastard.
他常拿雪茄燙我手臂 這該死的虐待狂
He used to put cigars out on my arm, the sadistic fuck.
他是個變態 就和你一樣
And he was a pervert, just like you.
我在九歲時殺了他
I killed him when I was nine years old.
你是誰
Who are you?
你女兒很特別
You have a real special daughter.
她理應得到自由
She deserves to be free.
你覺得你能進來拿走屬￿我的東西嗎
You think you can come in here and take that which belongs to me?
沒錯 你覺得呢
Yeah. What do you think?
神會從天而降來救你?
That god's gonna come down here and save you?
我就如神
I am as god.
祂也如我
He is as I am.
我會愛你的
I will love you.
你要學會愛我
And you will learn to love me.
- 這是神的旨意 - 我要殺了你
- It is god's will. - I will kill you.
這阻止不了我
That would not stop me.
你瘋了
You're mad.
那個人是誰
Who was that man?
他給你灌輸了愚蠢的想法
He put foolish thoughts in your mind.
他幫助了我 我愛他
He helped me. I love him.
不是 那不是愛
No, you do not.
那是淫欲
It is lust.
是愛
Yes.
我要打得你不再像你母親那樣
I will beat your mother out of you.
是時候了
The time has come.
我會溫柔的
I will be gentle.
譯{}者{}:{}微{}博{}@{}E{}m{}t{}e{}e
第四章
懲罰
他不會罷休的 對嗎
He ain't never gonna stop, is he?
我不會有事的
I'll be fine.
我們到了嗎
Are we there yet?
快回去睡覺
什麽情况
What was that?
放手 放開我
No, let me go!
- 待在那 - 馬修
- Stay there! - Matthew!
珊慕 不管有什麽事都別出來
Stay there, Sam. Whatever happens!
馬修
Matthew!
媽媽
Mama!
馬修
Matthew!
莉茲
Oh, Liz...
我一直希望這地方有朝一日會屬￿伊萊
I'd always hoped this place would be Eli's someday.
我意思是...
I mean...
他可以...
He could've...
怎麽說呢
I don't know...
弄個伐木場什麽的...
A sawmill or something...
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
你以前開過槍嗎
Have you ever fired one of those things before?
這是我的戰鬥
拿槍的應該是我
I should be the one holding the gun.
我要你留下陪珊慕
那麽遠開槍毫無用處
There's no use shooting from that distance.
這比你料想的更難
It's more difficult than you think,
尤其用這樣的槍
especially with a gun like that.
在畢斯瑪司時 我真的準備好原諒你了
I was truly prepared to forgive you, back in bismuth.
我愛你
I loved you.
你應該知道
You should have seen that.
可你却違抗我
You've turned against me,
就像你母親那樣
just like your mother.
但我再次被給予了另一個選擇
But again, I have been provided with an alternative.
沒錯 喬安娜
That's right, Joanna.
你女兒會爲你的所作所爲受苦
Your daughter shall suffer for your actions.
我責打她時 我會讓你看著
And I will make you watch as I chastise her.
之後 你會目睹我是如何讓她變成女人的
And after that, you will witness how i make her a woman.
你覺得她在裏面是安全的?
You believe she's safe in there?
我接近不了她?
That I cannot get to her?
你把她單獨留下了 喬安娜
You left her alone, Joanna.
永遠不要把你的心愛之人單獨留下
Never leave your loved ones alone.
你現在應該懂了
You should know that by now.
我能對你做的最壞的事是什麽呢 喬安娜
What is the worst thing i could do to you, Joanna?
幸好她睡著了
Lucky for her, she was asleep.
她什麽都沒看見
She did not see a thing.
怎麽了
Huh, what...
要防備假先知
Beware of false prophets
他們到你們這裏來 外面披著羊皮
who come to you in sheep's clothing...
裏面却是殘暴的狼
For inwardly, they are ravening wolves.
媽媽
Mama!
不 媽媽 媽媽
No, mama! Mama!
不
No!
媽媽
Mama!
我對你女兒會完全照做我對你所做的
I will do to your daughter exactly as I did to you.
我會儘量傷害你
I am going to hurt you as much as I can.
我就讓門開著
I will leave the door open.
我給你帶了這個過來
I brought you this.
你母親跟你說了成爲女人意味著什麽嗎
Has your mother told you what it means to be a woman?
許多人認爲神不贊成暴力
Many people believe that god does not approve of violence.
他們就沒讀過他們的聖經
They have not read their Bible.
暴力潔淨罪惡 淨化心靈
"Violence cleanses evil. It purifies the heart."
你的心靈需要淨化嗎
Does your heart need purifying?
你有過不好的念頭嗎
Have you had bad thoughts?
或許和男人有關?
About men, perhaps?
你喜歡男人嗎
Do you like men?
你出過血嗎
Have you bled yet?
我是個注定要遭厄運的人 珊慕
I am a doomed man, Sam.
已無法被拯救
Beyond salvation.
我想做什麽就做什麽
I can do whatever I want.
小女孩仍有著純潔的氣息
Young girls still carry the scent of innocence.
年長的女人聞上去就不同
Older women smell different.
是時候了
The time has come.
人們覺得地獄難以忍受是因爲那裏的烈焰
People think it's the flames that make hell unbearable.
幷不是這樣
It's not.
而是因爲沒有愛
It is the absence of love.
嘿
Hey.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
呀...
Well...
好久不見 莉茲
Long time no see, Liz.
那時我崩潰了
I was a broken man.
無法繼續在那生活
Couldn't go on living there.
好在新來的傳教士指引了我
Good thing the new preacher showed me
讓我去別處試試
I had to go try somewhere else.
是他告訴我畢斯瑪司在招副警長
He was the one, told me they was lookin' for deputies up in bismuth.
我在那開啓了新的生活
I made myself up a new life there.
大約一年前 那裏的警長遭到了槍擊
About a year ago, the sheriff there got himself shot.
我被選任代替他的位置
And I was chosen to replace him.
我清理他的辦公室時
And while I was cleaning out his office...
通緝令 2500美元賞金
犯謀殺罪 伊麗莎白·布蘭迪 啞巴 沒舌頭
發現了這個
I found this.
你本該改名的 莉茲
You should've changed your name, Liz.
你覺得世界上叫
How many Elizabeth brundys
伊麗莎白·布蘭迪的人有多少
you figure there are in this world?
而又有多少是沒舌頭的
And how many of 'em you figure don't got no tongue?
伊麗莎白·布蘭迪
Elizabeth brundy,
你因謀殺你的前雇主兼弗蘭克的地獄的業主
I hereby arrest you for the murder of frank blain,
弗蘭克·布萊恩 而被捕了
your former employer and proprietor of frank's inferno.
你逃不出你過去的所作所爲 莉茲
Your past done caught up with you, Liz.
時光荏苒 影像迷離
As life progresses, images blur.
獨留回憶
All that remains are memories.
我清楚地記得她
I remember her well.
她是一名戰士
She was a warrior.
始終掌控一切
Always in control.
我常會想她下沉時在想什麽
I've often wondered what she was thinking about on her way down.
我會想她想到了我
I like to think she thought of me.
我會想她知道我長大後會變得堅强
I like to think she knew I would grow up to be strong.
我清楚地記得她
I remember her well.
至少我覺得是這樣
At least I think I do.
我感覺她一直在我身邊
It feels like she always stayed with me.
看守著我
Watching over me.
保護著我
Protecting me.
嘿 快來 放下那東西
Hey, come on. Put that down.
媽媽
Mama?
走嗎
You coming?
譯者:微博@Emtee